FIELD NETWORK ENGINEER

Career Overview

Excellent Communication, Organizational, Prioritizing and Multi-tasking skills.

Seeking to benefit from an IT Department with complex technical knowledge and strong leadership skills.

*10+ Years of extensive computer experience and support.

Certified with all HP, Canon, Konica and Lexmark printers and copiers.

Technical Customer Service Specialist with a vast knowledge of web applications, software and framework seeking to assist clients in all troubleshooting endeavors.

Highly effective Customer Service Representative with a varied background. Seeking a challenging Network Security position in an industry-leading firm

Qualifications

- Technical help desk experience
- Local remoter systems support
- Proficiency in TCP/IP protocols
- GUI and tools
- Proficient in AVG, Printers, PC Security systems
- Mobile application development
- Excellent problem solving skills
- Customer needs assessment
- Windows XP/Vista
- DHCP/DNS Ethernet and Firewall proficient

Accomplishments

Network Security Â

- Planned, installed, maintained and optimized documentation of all LAN/WAN/VPN network hardware and software, security systems and communication links.
- Managed all clients network LAN/WAN hardware including routers, switches, load balancers and wireless networking equipment.

Network Support Â

- Acted as first point of contact for all major technical issues, including power outages, system failures and disaster recovery.
- Oversaw infrastructure of three offices and acted as support for help-desk technicians and IT Department.

Work Experience

Field Network Engineer, 10/2014 to Current Banner Health i1/4 Chandler, AZ

- Provide IT generalist support to customers while building greater technical understanding and awareness.
- Document and resolve incoming service requests and alerts, including escalations and manufacturer support.
- Collaborate with colleagues to achieve superior customer service.
- Answer support phone calls on a daily basis.
- Increase responsiveness and implement permanent resolution of issues by identifying trends in service histories.
- Create and publish documentation in the knowledge base.
- Contribute to and maintain system, installation, and configuration standards and procedures.
- Share newly acquired information with peers to improve support team capabilities.
- Comply with internal security controls and procedures for Loffler and customers.
- Provide mentoring and training of other engineers.
- Monitor service boards and work service requests or route to appropriate team members.
- · Approach technical issues with root cause discovery and resolution in mind.
- Identify resources and assign tasks commensurate with skillset and availability.
- Pursue mastery of an identified IT specialty that provides teammates a go-to resource.
- Assist with development of Loffler product stack.
- Act as technical lead on projects.
- Assist with changes to Loffler IT tools and systems.
- Architect advanced IT solutions.
- Other related duties as assigned.

Emergency Room Technician, 04/2014 to 10/2014 Banner Health i1/4 Mesa, AZ

- Operate equipment, such as electrocardiograms (EKGs), external defibrillators, or bag valve mask resuscitators, in advanced life support environments.
- Coordinate with treatment center personnel to obtain patients' vital statistics and medical history, to determine the circumstances of the emergency, and to administer emergency treatment.
- Coordinate work with other emergency medical team members or police or fire department personnel.
- Attend training classes to maintain certification licensure, keep abreast of new developments in the field, or maintain existing knowledge.
- Administer drugs, orally or by injection, or perform intravenous procedures under a physician's direction.
- Perform emergency diagnostic and treatment procedures, such as stomach suction, airway management, or heart monitoring, during ambulance ride.
- Observe, record, and report to physician the patient's condition or injury, the treatment provided, and reactions to drugs or treatment.
- Immobilize patient for placement on stretcher and ambulance transport, using backboard or other spinal immobilization device.
- Assess nature and extent of illness or injury to establish and prioritize medical procedures.
- Comfort and reassure patients.
- Administer first aid treatment or life support care to sick or injured persons in prehospital settings.

Emergency Room Technician, 03/2011 to 04/2014 Little Lake City Elementary i1/4 Santa Fe Springs, CA

- Administer first aid treatment or life support care to sick or injured persons in prehospital settings.
- Perform emergency diagnostic and treatment procedures, such as stomach suction, airway management, or heart monitoring, during ambulance ride.
- Observe, record, and report to physician the patient's condition or injury, the treatment provided, and reactions to drugs or treatment.
- Immobilize patient for placement on stretcher and ambulance transport, using backboard or other spinal immobilization device.
- Assess nature and extent of illness or injury to establish and prioritize medical procedures.
- Comfort and reassure patients.
- Operate equipment, such as electrocardiograms (EKGs), external defibrillators, or bag valve mask resuscitators, in advanced life support environments.
- Coordinate with treatment center personnel to obtain patients' vital statistics and medical history, to determine the circumstances of the emergency, and to administer emergency treatment.

Computer Field Technician, 02/2005 to 03/2011 APEX COMPUTER SYSTEMS, INC 11/4 City, STATE

- Update knowledge and skills to keep up with rapid advancements in computer technology.
- Provide technical support to designers, marketing and sales departments, suppliers, engineers and other team members throughout the
 product development and implementation process.
- Test and verify hardware and support peripherals to ensure that they meet specifications and requirements, by recording and analyzing test data.
- Monitor functioning of equipment and make necessary modifications to ensure system operates in conformance with specifications.
- Analyze information to determine, recommend, and plan layout, including type of computers and peripheral equipment modifications.
- Build, test, and modify product prototypes using working models or theoretical models constructed with computer simulation.
- Analyze user needs and recommend appropriate hardware.
- Direct technicians, engineering designers or other technical support personnel as needed.
- Confer with engineering staff and consult specifications to evaluate interface between hardware and software and operational and performance requirements of overall system.
- Select hardware and material, assuring compliance with specifications and product requirements.
- Store, retrieve, and manipulate data for analysis of system capabilities and requirements.

NREMT / Fire Fighter , 08/2003 to 10/2010 ROGERS FIRE DEPT il/4 City , STATE

- Rescue victims from burning buildings and accident sites.
- Search burning buildings to locate fire victims.
- Administer first aid and cardiopulmonary resuscitation to injured persons.
- Dress with equipment such as fire resistant clothing and breathing apparatus.
- Drive and operate fire fighting vehicles and equipment.
- Move toward the source of a fire using knowledge of types of fires, construction design, building materials, and physical layout of properties.
- Respond to fire alarms and other calls for assistance, such as automobile and industrial accidents.
- Assess fires and situations and report conditions to superiors to receive instructions, using two-way radios.
- Position and climb ladders to gain access to upper levels of buildings, or to rescue individuals from burning structures.
- Collaborate with police to respond to accidents, disasters, and arson investigation calls.
- Take action to contain hazardous chemicals that might catch fire, leak, or spill.
- Prepare written reports that detail specifics of fire incidents.
- Inspect fire sites after flames have been extinguished to ensure that there is no further danger.
- Participate in courses, seminars and conferences, and study fire science literature, to learn firefighting techniques.
- Inspect buildings for fire hazards and compliance with fire prevention ordinances, testing and checking smoke alarms and fire suppression

equipment as necessary.

Laser Printer / Computer / Networking Technician, 11/2001 to 09/2005 MATRIX LASER CARE il/4 City, STATE

- Converse with customers to determine details of equipment problems.
- Reassemble machines after making repairs or replacing parts.
- Travel to customers' stores or offices to service machines or to provide emergency repair service.
- Reinstall software programs or adjust settings on existing software to fix machine malfunctions.
- Advise customers concerning equipment operation, maintenance, or programming.
- Test new systems to ensure that they are in working order.
- Assemble machines according to specifications, using hand or power tools and measuring devices.
- Operate machines to test functioning of parts or mechanisms.
- Maintain records of equipment maintenance work or repairs.
- Install and configure new equipment, including operating software or peripheral equipment.
- Maintain parts inventories and order any additional parts needed for repairs.
- Update existing equipment, performing tasks such as installing updated circuit boards or additional memory.
- Align, adjust, or calibrate equipment according to specifications.
- Test components or circuits of faulty equipment to locate defects, using oscilloscopes, signal generators, ammeters, voltmeters, or special diagnostic software programs.
- Repair, adjust, or replace electrical or mechanical components or parts, using hand tools, power tools, or soldering or welding equipment.
- Complete repair bills, shop records, time cards, or expense reports.
- Disassemble machines to examine parts, such as wires, gears, or bearings for wear or defects, using hand or power tools and measuring devices.

Education and Training

High School Diploma : June 1995 Excel High School i $^1\!/_4$ City , State , United States Skills

ambulance, Approach, Architect, hardware, conferences, customer service, direction, documentation, EKGs, equipment maintenance, equipment operation, expense reports, first aid, hand tools, hardware and support, Inspect, layout, life support, marketing and sales, materials, mechanical, memory, mentoring, access, oscilloscopes, peripherals, personnel, police, power tools, product development, programming, Maintain records, recording, repairs, resuscitation, seminars, signal generators, simulation, soldering, statistics, technical support, phone, type, welding, written